Guide to the United Methodist Church Records, 1784-1984, bulk 1800-1940
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Historical Sketches Series, 1786-1997 and undated, (3 boxes)
  - Churches and Cities Subseries, 1887-1997 and undated
    - Rock Springs Camp Meeting, Lincoln Co., Rock Springs Charge, 1987, 1988
    - Salem UMC, probably Sampson Co., Garland Charge, Magnolia Ct., 1969
    - Salisbury Church, undated
    - Shallotte Village Church, near Southport, Brunswick Ct., Wilmington Dist., 1895
    - Sharon Church, near Southport, Brunswick Co., Brunswick Ct., Wilmington Dist., 1895
    - Sharon Church, Lenoir Co., Grifton Ct.
    - Shilo Church, probably Dallas, probably Shelby Dist., 1879
    - Southport Church, undated
    - St. Francis MECS, Bertie Co., Lewiston Ct., Warrenton Dist., 1895
    - St. Mary's MECS, probably Bertie Co., Lewiston Ct., Warrenton Dist., 1895-1896
    - Statesville Church, Iredell Co., probably Iredell Ct., undated
    - Trinity Church, Durham, Durham Co., 1887
      Includes Main Street Church and Carr Church.
    - Trinity Church, probably Lenoir Co., LaGrange Ct., New Bern Dist., undated
    - Trinity Church, near Waycross, probably Sampson Co., Black River Ct., undated
    - Trinity UMC, Charleston, S.C., 1978
    - Wesley's Chapel UMC, Franklin Co., Ebenezer-Wesley's Chapel Charge, circa 1988
    - Wilson Methodist Church, Wilson Co., Edgecombe Ct., undated
    - Winston Church, undated
    - Zion Church, near Wilmington, Brunswick Co., Brunswick Ct., Wilmington Dist., 1895
  - Counties and Circuits Subseries, 1844-1925 and undated
    Contains handwritten or typescript short essays by ministers describing the religious activities of their circuits and in their counties, especially in the late 1890s. Also includes other resource material compiled by church historians or church history committees, especially newspaper clippings, church newsletters or other essays, and transcriptions and/or copies of other letters or clippings.
    - List of sketches, approximately 1895 (Box HS2)
    - Anson Co., 1967
    - Bladen Ct., probably Bladen Co., undated
    - Burlington Ct., probably Caswell Co., 1890
    - Carteret Co., undated
    - Columbus Ct., undated
    - Dallas Ct., Shelby Dist., 1879
    - Dare Co., undated
    - Elizabeth Ct., Bladen Co., undated
    - Goldsboro Ct., probably Wayne Co., 1895
    - Granville Co., Granville Ct., 1879
      Includes Vance Co.
    - Harrellsville Ct., undated
      First in Va. Conference, later in N.C. Conference.
    - [Haw River Ct., Chatham Co., Lee Co., Harnett Co., Pittsboro, undated: Found in Hew Hope Ct.]
    - Lincoln Co., 1925
    - Magnolia Ct., probably Sampson Co., Duplin Co., Wilmington, Kennansville, Magnolia, 1876
    - New Hope Ct., undated
      Includes Haw River Ct. and Pittsboro Ct.
    - North Guilford Ct., undated
    - [Pittsboro Ct., undated: Found in New Hope Ct.]
    - Stokes Ct., Stokes Co., undated
    - Tar River Ct., undated
    - Trent Ct., probably Craven Co., 1844
    - [Vance Co., undated: Found in Granville Co.]
    - Waccamaw Ct., undated
      Includes Whiteville Ct.
    - Wayne Co., 1879
    - [Whiteville Ct., undated: Found in Waccamaw Ct.]
    - Wilkes Co., 1879
  - Methodism Subseries, 1821-1944
    Comprises essays or other longer written works that cover the history and development of Methodism generally, primarily in N.C. and the South, especially handwritten or typescript drafts of articles, these, or speeches published elsewhere. Also includes a few letters or extracts from letters, the contents of which appear to have been solicited by H.T. Hudson in 1879.
    - Camp Meetings in North Carolina, by Rev. Henry Hardy, 1821 (Box HS2)
    - A Central Illinois Methodist Minister, 1857-1891, by Phineas L. Windsor, 1944
      Biographical sketch of author's father, Rev. John Alexander Windsor.
    - Fresh Light on the Early History of Methodism in NC to 1800, by Rev. A. R. Goodchild, 1897
    - History of Methodism in North Carolina, by Rev. J. A. Baldwin, 1893
    - [History of Methodism in North Carolina, by P. F. W. Stamey: Found in Historical Sketches Series, Ministers Subseries, Stamey, P. F. W.]
    - History of Methodism in North Carolina in the Eighteenth Century, by Rev. H. Willis, graduate thesis (handwritten and typescript copies), 1893, (2 folders)
    - History of the MECS, in the State of North Carolina, by Hilary T. Hudson, circa 1870-1880
    - [ Methodism in Guilford County, by J. W. Shelton, 1879: Found in Historical Sketches Series, Ministers Subseries, Shelton, J. W.]
    - Methodism in High Point, by Dred Peacock, 1916
    - Methodism in Virginia, 1806-1832, by A. R. Bernard, 1859 June 8 (Box HS3)
    - [ Pioneer Methodism in Virginia, Centennial Address, approximately 1884: Found in Historical Sketches Series, Ministers Subseries, Bennett, William Wallace.]
    - [ Sketch for the History of Methodism in NC, by H. P. Wangh, 1879: Found in Historical Sketches Series, Ministers Subseries, Wangh, H. P.]
    - [Statement of Facts concerning the state of Methodism in the eastern shore of Va. during the Civil War, by William Gwynn Coe, circa 1864: Found in the Historical Sketches Series, Ministers Subseries, Coe, William Gwynn. See also the Non-N.C. Conference Series, Va. Conference Subseries, Conference-level records, Responses of eastern shore of Va. to church split, 1864-1866.]
    - The Story of Trans-Mississippi Methodism, by Paul Neff Garber, undated
    - Some First Things in North Carolina Methodism, by Rev. W. L. Grissom, 1908
  - Ministers Subseries, 1786-1996 and undated, bulk 1786-1889
    Contains handwritten biographical information supplied by individual ministers about their careers and activities in N.C., solicited by H. T. Hudson in 1879. Also includes sermon texts, correspondence, funeral service/memorial texts, and elder, deacon, and preacher's licenses. There are several documents--land deeds for churches and correspondence--written by or pertaining to Francis Asbury and Thomas Coke. William Wallace Bennett is also among the ministers represented in this subseries. Finally, there is also a handwritten statement (1864) by William Gwynn Cole regarding the response of the Methodist churches in the eastern shore of Va. to the splintering of the Methodist Episcopal church over slavery. For related material, see also the Non-N.C. Conference Series, Va. Conference Subseries, Conference-level records, Responses of eastern shore of Va. to church split, 1864-1866.
    - Abernethy, Robert Laban, Happy Home, N.C., circa 1879 (Box HS3)
    - Albea, William W., Notebook, 1833-1848
    - Asbury, Francis (Photostatic copies available.)
      - Deeds to land
        - Chatham Co., from Isaac Cox to Asbury, 1789
          Deed for Old Asbury Church and/or Rocky River Church.
        - Gates Co., from Jethro Benton to Asbury and Thomas Coke, 1786
      - Letters
        - 1803 June 27, To Stith Mead (copy), Cambridge, N.Y.
        - 1806 Feb. 23, To Mary Asbury? Pilkinton, Isle of White, Va.?
      - Print of Arnold Home, Spottsylvania Co., Va., where Asbury died, undated
    - Bennett, William Wallace
      - Pioneer Methodism in Virginia, Centennial Address, Randolph Macon College, Ashland, Va., circa 1884
      - Sermons, Alexandria and Richmond, Va., 1858-1859 and undated
      - Memorial, 1887
    - Betts, Alex Davis, circa 1879
    - Bobbitt, James B., circa 1987
    - Boone, Thomas A., circa 1879
    - [Burkhead, Lingurn Skidmore, 1865: Found in Historical Sketches Series, Churches and Cities Subseries, Front Street Church.]
    - Campbell, Thomas S., probably 1879
    - Carraway, Paul Jones, Winston, N.C., 1879
    - Charbonnel, F., 1880
      Letter to Dr. Hudson from a Canadian minister.
    - Coke, Thomas, Sermon, Baltimore, Md., 1785 March 1 (Photostatic copy available. See also Asbury, Francis.)
    - Coe, William Gwynn, Statement of Facts concerning the state of Methodism in the eastern shore of Va. during the Civil War, circa 1864
      (See also the Non-N.C. Conference Series, Va. Conference Subseries, Conference-level records, Responses of eastern shore of Va. to church split, 1864-1866.)
    - Creasy, Walter S., Surry Ct., circa 1879
    - Cuninggim, Jesse Anderson, circa 1879
    - Dodson, Charles C., Thomasville, S.C., 1879
    - Ervin, James Sherrod, Lenoir Ct., circa 1879
    - Eudaily, Elisha James, circa 1879
    - [Freeman, Evan, 1844: Found in Historical Sketches Series, Counties and Circuits Subseries, Trent Ct.]
    - Gattis, Thomas Jefferson, circa 1879
    - [Gray, Alson (1799-1880), Randolph Co., 1996: Found in Historical Sketches Series, Churches and Cities Subseries, Gray's Chapel MPC.]
    - Hancock, John (1763-1832), Montgomery Co., N.C., 1996
    - Hardison, George Washington, circa 1879
    - Heill, James, Notebook, 1804
    - Jurney, N. M., circa 1879
    - Moser, James Franklin, N.C., 1967
    - Nash, Leonidas, L., circa 1879
    - Nicholson, David B., undated
    - Overman, John P., letters and other material, Elizabeth City, N.C., 1897-1898
    - Pegram, Thomas Howard, Stokes Ct., circa 1879
    - Perkins, E. L., circa 1879
    - Pickens, R. W., License as a Deacon (MECS), Holston Conference, 1847
      Signed by Bishop James Osgood Andrews.
    - Pope, Erskin, Greensboro, N.C., 1884-1889
    - Rich, John, N.C., undated
    - Riley, Simpson, Richmond, 1864
      Funeral sermon preached by Rev. Archibald A. McMennen, Orange Co., N.C.
    - Sharpe, Van Buren A., circa 1879
    - Shelton, J. W., Guilford Co., 1879
    - Sherrill, M. V., Olin, N.C., 1879
    - Simpson, James P., circa 1879
    - Stacy, Lucius E., circa 1879
    - Stamey, P. F. W., Morganton Ct., Burke Co., N.C., circa 1879
    - Steele, William, Letter to Bill, 1856
    - Tabor, John Boring, Statesville, N.C., undated
    - Thompson, L. E., Montgomery Ct., circa 1879
    - Wangh, H. P., 1879
    - Willson, James, circa 1879
    - [Windsor, John Alexander: Found in Historical Sketches Series, Methodism Subseries, A Central Illinois Methodist Minister.]
    - Wood, Marquis Lafayette, circa 1879
      Includes a newspaper clipping on Robert Paine.
    - Wyche, Ira T., Albermarle Ct., circa 1879
    - Yates, Edwin Asbury, circa 1879
    - Multiple ministers, several states, correspondence and list of names, 1821-1872 and undated, (2 folders)
      Includes Washington, District of Columbia; Charleston and Sumter, S.C.; Robeson Co., N.C.; Statesville, N.C.; Louisburg, N.C.; New York; and Wesleyan University, Bloomington, Ill.
    - Unidentified, sermon, undated
- Oversize Materials
  - National Records Series
    - Methodist Episcopal Church, South Subseries
      - Missionary Society, Membership Certificate, 1857 (Opaperfolder 1)
      - Reunification, Judicial Council, Copy of photograph of attendees at the General Conference, 1906 (Opaperfolder 2)
  - N.C. Conference Records Series
    - Conference Records Subseries
      - Conference attendees, photograph and list of names, 1887 (51st annual conference) (Opaperfolder 3)
      - Trials of Ministers (Opaperfolder 4)
        - MECS vs L. L. Hendren, 1885
    - District Records Subseries
      - Wilmington District, 1866-1898 (Box OS1)
        - District Conference Records, 1866-1898(F-2908)
      - Wilson District, 1892-1894 (Box OS2)
        - District Conference Minutes, 1892-1894(F-2926)
    - Circuit, Charge, and Church Records Subseries
      - Beaufort Co., 1860-1902
        - Bath Circuit, Washington District, Church Records, 1860-1902(F-2892) (Box OS3)
      - Bladen Co., 1898-1930
        - Elizabeth Circuit/Charge, multiple districts, Church Register, No. 2, 1898-1930
      - Cleveland Co., 1877-1880
        - Rock Spring Circuit, Shelby District, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1877-1880(F-2890)
      - Gates Co., 1784-1840, 1866-1877, 1884-1937
        - Gates Circuit, multiple districts, Church Register, 1784-1840, 1866-1877(F-5016) (Box OS4)
        - North Gates Circuit, multiple districts, Church Register, 1884-1937(F-5013) (Box OS5)
      - Warren Co., 1888-1894
        - Henderson Station, Raleigh District, Treasurer's Book, 1888-1894(F-6620) (Box OS4)
  - Western N.C. Conference Records Series
    - Conference Records Subseries
      - Journal of the Western N.C. Conference, 1902-1905(F-4289) (Box OS6)
    - District Records Subseries
      - Charlotte District (Box OS7)
        - District Conference Minutes, 1913-1932(F-4289)
    - Circuit, Charge, and Church Records Subseries
      - Randolph Co. (Box OS6)
        - Randolph Circuit/Charge, Greensboro District, Church Register, 1902-1928(F-2962)
        - West Randolph Circuit, Greensboro District, Circuit Register, 1902-1906(F-2961)
Circuit, Charge, and Station Index
Lists in alphabetical order all circuit, charge, and station names found in this finding aid and gives their box location. This index is not an inclusive list of all circuits, charges, and stations that may be found in this collection. Users are encouraged to consult the quarterly conference minutes for the geographical area or county in which they are interested to find additional references to other circuits, charges, and stations.
Alamance Circuit, Western N.C. Conference, Alamance Co., Box WNC9
Ansonville Circuit, N.C. Conference, Anson Co., Box NCC31
Bath Circuit, N.C. Conference, Beaufort Co., Box NCC32 Box OS3
Bridgewater Circuit, Balt. Conference, Unknown Co., Box NNC1
Buckhorn Circuit, N.C. Conference, Alamance and Wake Cos., Box NCC31 Box NCC57
Burlington Charge/Station, N.C. and Va. Conferences, Alamance Co., Box NCC31
Burlington, Graham, and Haw River Charge, N.C. Conference, Alamance Co., Box NCC31
Camden Circuit, N.C. and Va. Conferences, Camden Co., Boxes NCC34-NCC35
Cape Fear Circuit, N.C. Conference, Brunswick Co., Box NCC34
Cary Circuit, N.C. Conference, Wake Co., Box NCC58
Caswell Circuit, N.C. Conference, Caswell Co., Box NCC35
Catawba Circuit, Western N.C. Conference, Catawba Co., Box WNC11
Cedar Falls Station and Franklinsville, N.C. and Va. Conferences, Randolph Co., Box NCC56
Chatham Circuit, N.C. and Va. Conferences, Chatham Co., Box NCC38
Chowan Circuit, N.C. Conference, Chowan Co., Box NCC39
Columbia Circuit, N.C. Conference, Tyrell Co., Box NCC57
Currituck Circuit, N.C. and Va. Conferences, Currituck Co., Box NCC40
Dare Circuit, N.C. and Va. Conferences, Dare Co., Box NCC40
Double Shoals Circuit, N.C. Conference, Cleveland Co., Box NCC39
Double Shoals and Polkville Circuit, Western N.C. Conference, Cleveland Co., Box WNC11
Durham Circuit, N.C. Conference, Durham Co., Boxes NCC45-NCC46
Elizabeth Circuit/Charge, N.C. Conference, Bladen Co., Box NCC32 Box OS3
Elizabeth City Station, N.C. Conference, Pasquotank Co., Box NCC53
Fifth Street Charge/Church/Station, N.C. Conference, New Hanover Co., Boxes NCC52-NCC53
Forsyth Circuit, N.C. Conference, Forsyth Co., Box NCC48
Franklinsville and Cedar Falls Station, N.C. and Va. Conferences, Randolph Co., Box NCC56
Franklinsville Circuit, N.C. and Va. Conferences, Randolph Co., Box NCC56
Gaston Circuit, N.C. Conference, Gaston Co., Box NCC48
Gates Circuit, N.C. and Va. Conference, Gates Co., Box NCC48 Box OS4
Guilford Circuit, N.C. Conference, Guilford Co., Box NCC50
Hatteras Circuit, N.C. Conference, Dare Co., Boxes NCC40-NCC41
Hatteras and Ocracoke Circuit, N.C. Conference, Pamlico and Dare Cos., Boxes NCC53
Haw River Circuit, N.C. Conference, Alamance Co., Box NCC31
Henderson Station, N.C. Conference, Warren Co., Box NCC58 Box OS4
Hertford Circuit, N.C. and Va. Conferences, Perquimans Co., Boxes NCC53-NCC55
Iredell Circuit, N.C. and Va. Conferences, Iredell Co., Box NCC51
Iredell Charge, Western N.C. Conference, Iredell Co., Box WNC12
Jefferson Circuit, Balt. Conference, Unknown Co., Box NNC1
Jefferson Circuit, Western N.C. Conference, Ashe Co., Boxes WNC9-WNC10
Kitty Hawk Charge, N.C. Conference, Dare Co., Box NCC41
Kitty Hawk Circuit, N.C. Conference, Dare Co., Box NCC41
Leasburg Circuit, N.C. Conference, Caswell Co., Boxes NCC35-NCC37
Lexington Circuit, Western N.C. Conference, Davidson Co., Box WNC11
Lincolnton Circuit, N.C. and S.C. Conferences, Lincoln Co., Boxes NCC51-NCC52
Lincolnton Station, N.C. Conference, Lincoln Co., Box NCC52
Milton Circuit/Charge, N.C. Conference, Caswell Co., Box NCC37
Montgomery Circuit, N.C. Conference, Montgomery Co., Box NCC52
Monroe, Matthews and Clear Creek Circuits, N.C. Conference, Union Co.?, Boxes NCC57-NCC57A
Morganton Circuit, N.C. Conference, Burke Co., Box NCC34
Morganton Circuit, Western N.C. Conference, Burke Co., Box WNC10
Moyock Circuit, N.C. Conference, Currituck Co., Box NCC40
Newport and Trent Circuits, N.C. Conference, Cartaret and Craven Cos., Box NCC35
North Gates Charge, N.C. Conference, Gates Co., Box NCC50
North Gates Circuit, N.C. and Va. Conferences, Gates Co., Box NCC50 Box OS5
Okracoke and Hatteras Circuit, N.C. Conference, Pamlico and Dare Cos., Box NCC53
Pantego Circuit/Charge, N.C. Conference, Beaufort Co., Box NCC32
Pasquotank Circuit, N.C. Conference, Camden and Pasquotank Cos., Box NCC35 Boxes NCC53-NCC54
Perquimans Circuit, N.C. and Va. Conferences, Perquimans Co., Boxes NCC55-NCC56
Pittsboro Circuit, N.C. Conference, Alamance and Chatham Cos., Box NCC31
Pittsboro Circuit/Church/Charge, N.C. Conference, Chatham Co., Boxes NCC38-NCC39
Pleasant Garden Circuit, N.C. Conference, Guilford Co., Box NCC50
Pleasant Hill Circuit, Ala. Conference, Dallas Co., Box NNC1
Polkville Circuit, Western N.C. Conference, Cleveland Co., Box WNC11
Polkville and Double Shoals Circuit, Western N.C. Conference, Cleveland Co., Box WNC11
Randolph Circuit, N.C. Conference, Randolph Co., Boxes NCC56-NCC57
Randolph Circuit, Western N.C. Conference, Randolph Co., Boxes WNC14-WNC16
Roanoke Circuit, N.C. Conference, Halifax Co., Box NCC50
Roanoke Island Circuit/Station, N.C. and Va. Conferences, Dare Co., Boxes NCC41-NCC42
Rock Spring Circuit, N.C. Conference, Cleveland Co., Box NCC40 Box NCC58
Shelby Station and Central Shelby Circuit, Western N.C. Conference, Cleveland Co., Box WNC11
South Camden Circuit, N.C. Conference, Camden Co., Box NCC35
South Guilford Circuit, N.C. Conference, Guilford Co., Box NCC50 Box NCC56
Stanley Creek Circuit, N.C. Conference, Gaston Co., Box NCC48
Stokes Circuit, N.C. Conference, Stokes Co., Box NCC57
Trinity College Circuit, N.C. Conference, Randolph Co., Box NCC50
Washington Station, N.C. Conference, Washington Co., Box NCC58
West Davie Circuit, Western N.C. Conference, Yadkin Co., Box WNC15
West Randolph Circuit, Western N.C. Conference, Randolph Co., Boxes WNC15-WNC16
Winston Circuit, Western N.C. Conference, Forsyth Co., Box WNC11
Woodsdale Circuit/Charge, N.C. Conference, Person Co., Box NCC56
Yanceyville Circuit, N.C. Conference, Caswell Co., Box NCC37
Church and Mission Index
Lists in alphabetical order all church and mission names found in this finding aid and gives their box location. This index is not an inclusive list of all churches and missions that may be found in this collection. Users are encouraged to consult the quarterly conference minutes for the geographical area or county in which they are interested to find additional references to other churches and missions.
Bethany Church, N.C. Conference, Caswell Co., Box NCC35
Bethany Church, N.C. Conference, [Unknown Co.], Box NCC58
Brindletown Church, N.C. Conference, Burke Co., Box NCC34
Broad Street Church, Western N.C. Conference, Iredell Co., Box WNC12
Buckhorn Church, N.C. Conference, Alamance and Wake Cos., Box NCC31 Box NCC57
Carr Church, N.C. Conference, Durham Co., Box NCC42
Church Street Church, Western N.C. Conference, Rowan Co., Box WNC15
Cokesbury Church, N.C. Conference, Alamance and Wake Cos., Box NCC31 Box NCC57
Currituck Mission, N.C. and Va. Conferences, Currituck Co., Box NCC40
Dare Mission, N.C. and Va. Conferences, Dare Co., Box NCC40
Duke Memorial Church, N.C. Conference, Durham Co., Boxes NCC42-NCC45
Elizabeth Circuit/Charge, N.C. Conference, Bladen Co., Box NCC32 Box NCC58
Fifth Street Charge/Church/Station, N.C. Conference, New Hanover Co., Boxes NCC52-NCC53
First Methodist Church, N.C. Conference, Unknown Co., Box NCC58
First Methodist Church, Western N.C. Conference, Lincoln Co., Box WNC12
Front Street Church, N.C. Conference, Durham Co., Box NCC46
Gregson Street Church, N.C. Conference, Durham Co., Box NCC46
Guilford Mission, N.C. Conference, Guilford Co., Box NCC56
Hertford Church, N.C. Conference, Perquimans Co., Box NCC54
Hopewell Church, Western N.C. Conference, Catawba Co., Box WNC11
Kitrell's Church, N.C. Conference, Pasquotank Co., Box NCC53
Kitty Hawk Mission, N.C. Conference, Dare Co., Box NCC41
Leasburg Church, N.C. Conference, Caswell Co., Box NCC35
Main Street Church/Charge, N.C. Conference, Durham Co., Boxes NCC46-NCC47
Milton Circuit/Charge, N.C. Conference, Caswell Co., Box NCC37
Mt. Olivet Church, N.C. Conference, Montgomery Co., Box NCC52
Mt. Pleasant Church, N.C. Conference, Forsyth Co., Box NCC48
Pantego Circuit/Charge, N.C. Conference, Beaufort Co., Box NCC32
Pittsboro Circuit/Church/Charge, N.C Conference, Chatham Co., Boxes NCC38-NCC39
Polkville Church, Western N.C. Conference, Cleveland Co., Box WNC11
Roanoke Island Circuit/Station, N.C. and Va. Conferences, Dare Co., Boxes NCC41-NCC42
Salisbury [Street] Church, Western N.C. Conference, Rowan Co., Box WNC15
Singletary Church, N.C. Conference, Bladen Co., Box NCC34
Stokesburg Church, N.C. Conference, Stokes Co., Box NCC57
Tabernacle Church, N.C. Conference, Randolph Co., Box NCC57
Trinity College Church, N.C. Conference, Randolph Co., Box NCC57
Union Church, N.C. Conference, Caswell Co., Box NCC37
Union Church, N.C. Conference, Randolph Co., Box NCC57
Woodsdale Circuit/Charge, N.C. Conference, Person Co., Box NCC56
Baptismal Records Index, Methodist Episcopal Church, South
Arranged in three groupings: N.C. Conference, Western N.C. Conference, and Va. Conference, and then the records are listed by county. This index was compiled in 1968 and does not include any additions to the collection since then.
Bladen County: Elizabeth Circuit, Church Registers Nos. 1 and 2, 1888-1930, Box NCC32
Beaufort County: Bath Circuit, Church Records, 1860-1902, Box NCC32
Chatham County: Chatham Circuit, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1833-1941, Box NCC38
Chatham County: Pittsboro Circuit, Church Register, 1894-1901, Box NCC38
Cleveland County: Rock Spring Circuit, Church Register, 1881-1895, Box NCC40
Durham County: Carr Church, Register of Members, 1887-1897, Box NCC42
Durham County: Duke Memorial Church, Register of Members, 1885-1924, Box NCC43
Durham County: Durham Circuit, Church Registers, 1889-1906 and 1908-1925, Box NCC45
Durham County: Main Street Church, Registers of Members, 1885-1909 and 1890, Box NCC46
Gates County: North Gates Circuit, Church Register, 1884-1937, Box NCC50
Iredell County: Iredell Circuit, Church Records, 1834-1850, Box NCC50
New Hanover County: Fifth Street Church, Records, 1844-1870; Church Registers, 1851-1884 and 1885-1888, Box NCC50
Pasquotank Co.: Pasquotank Circuit, Church Register, 1854-1858 Box NCC53
Washington County: Washington Station, Church Register, 1887-1893, Box NCC58
Ashe Co.: Jefferson Circuit, Church Registers, 1893-1932 Boxes WNC9-WNC10
Burke Co.: Morganton Circuit, Church Register, 1889-1902, Box WNC10
Iredell Co.: Broad Street Church, Church Register, 1917-1924, Box WNC12
Lincoln Co.: First Methodist Church/Station, Church Register, 1909-1954, Box WNC12
Randolph Co.: Randolph Circuit, Church Register, 1902-1928, Box OS7
Randolph Co.: West Randolph Circuit, Church Register, 1902-1906 Box OS7
Va. Conference: Perquimans County: Hertford Circuit, Quarterly Conference Minutes, 1874-1891, Box NCC54